<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-08-16T00:16:19.162Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-08-16T00:16:19.162Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use JavaScript Promises – Callbacks, Async/Await, and Promise Methods Explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-promises-async-await-and-promise-methods/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-promises-async-await-and-promise-methods/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T16:03:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this tutorial, you will learn everything you need to know about using promises and async/await in JavaScript. So let's get started. If you'd like to learn along with a video version of this tutorial, you can also check out my YouTube playlist [https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4jaiXP6vU2w&list=PLSJnlFr3D-mGIHFpo80ylsaBErtueSpYS&index=14] . Why Use Promises in JavaScript?]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yogesh Chavan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ultimate Guide to High Performance WordPress]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-ultimate-guide-to-high-performance-wordpress/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-ultimate-guide-to-high-performance-wordpress/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T14:35:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are many strategies you can do to increase the performance of your WordPress websites and other websites. In this guide, we'll show you how to identify and fix performance issues for good. This guide combines over 20 years of experience of fine-tuning servers, CDNs, and website code to deliver]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beau Carnes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript Tips to Help You Build Better Web Development Projects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-tips-for-better-web-dev-projects/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-tips-for-better-web-dev-projects/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T14:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript is a widely used web programming language. If you're getting into software engineering or coding in particular and you want to focus on web development, learning JavaScript is probably the best thing to do. Learning JavaScript empowers you to create dynamic and interactive web experiences. And it lets you]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kolade Chris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modern Methods For Improving Drupal’s Largest Contentful Paint Core Web Vital]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/methods-improving-drupal-largest-contentful-paint-core-web-vital/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/methods-improving-drupal-largest-contentful-paint-core-web-vital/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The background image used in the hero component, which is slow to load, is a very common problem with any component that uses a large image file as a background image. In this article, Mike Herchel walks you through how to tackle this common performance issue using modern techniques.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Mike Herchel)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Web Scraping with Python and Beautiful Soup in Spanish – Course for Beginners]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-web-scraping-with-python-and-beautiful-soup-in-spanish-course-for-beginners/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/learn-web-scraping-with-python-and-beautiful-soup-in-spanish-course-for-beginners/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T04:50:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your goal is to collect data from websites automatically, web scraping may be exactly what you need. In this course, you will learn all the basics with exercises and practical projects. We published a course on the freeCodeCamp.org Spanish YouTube channel [https://www.youtube.com/freecodecampespanol] that will teach you how to use]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Estefania Cassingena Navone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's the Difference Between Default and Named Exports in JavaScript?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/difference-between-default-and-named-exports-in-javascript/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/difference-between-default-and-named-exports-in-javascript/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T16:36:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript is one of the most popular programming languages among web developers. And it offers multiple ways to organize and share code between different files.  When working with modules, you might come across two common ways of exporting: Default exports and Named exports.  Understanding the difference between these]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yazdun Fadali</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Become a Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-become-a-microsoft-learn-student-ambassador/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-become-a-microsoft-learn-student-ambassador/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T16:11:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors [https://mvp.microsoft.com/studentambassadors] program is a student-focused program designed to empower students to become advocates and leaders in the tech ecosystem.  Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors are student leaders who collaborate with Microsoft to help fellow students learn about technology and engage with various Microsoft technologies and]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Salim Oyinlola</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn JavaScript Operators – Logical, Comparison, Ternary, and More JS Operators With Examples]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-operators/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/javascript-operators/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T15:44:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript has many operators that you can use to perform operations on values and variables (also called operands) Based on the types of operations these JS operators perform, we can divide them up into seven groups:  1. Arithmetic Operators  2. Assignment Operators  3. Comparison Operators  4.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nathan Sebhastian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make AI Art with Stable Diffusion]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/stable-diffusion-crash-course/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/stable-diffusion-crash-course/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T13:35:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn how to make AI Art with Stable Diffusion]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lynn Zheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Knip: An Automated Tool For Finding Unused Files, Exports, And Dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/knip-automated-tool-find-unused-files-exports-dependencies/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/knip-automated-tool-find-unused-files-exports-dependencies/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most of the projects have at least a few unused files, exports, and dependencies lying around, often because it’s difficult knowing when one thing relies on another and scary removing something you’re not sure is in use. Lars Kappert shares a tool he’s been working on that offers a solution.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Lars Kappert)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use the WordPress Command Line Interface – WP-CLI Tutorial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-wordpress-cli/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-use-wordpress-cli/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T21:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the world of website development and content management, efficiency and automation are key. The WordPress Command Line Interface – or WP-CLI – is a powerful tool that can help you streamlines tasks and manage WordPress websites more effectively.  This article provides an overview of WP-CLI, focusing on its]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Venturi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Create a Meteor Effect with React and TailwindCSS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-a-meteor-effect-with-react-and-tailwindcss/</id>
        <link href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-create-a-meteor-effect-with-react-and-tailwindcss/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T16:14:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A while ago, I saw a post on Twitter that had some fancy beams of light emanating out from behind the main image. It looked like a meteor was blazing softly behind the card, and I thought it was a really cool UI component to have in a project.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manu Arora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing Accessible Text Over Images: Best Practices, Techniques And Resources (Part 2)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/designing-accessible-text-over-images-part2/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/designing-accessible-text-over-images-part2/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part 2 of the series, Hannah Milan reviews various accessible text over images techniques for designing your content, including framing the image, soft-colored gradients technique, text styles and text position, solid color shapes, and use of colored backgrounds.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Hannah Milan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running A Page Speed Test: Monitoring vs. Measuring]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/running-page-speed-test-monitoring-versus-measuring/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/running-page-speed-test-monitoring-versus-measuring/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What does your performance “stack” look like? There are all kinds of tools available for measuring page speed, but what data and assumptions do they use to measure performance? And speaking of *measuring* performance, there’s quite a difference between that and *monitoring* performance. Let’s dig in!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Geoff Graham)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Friction As A Feature In Machine Learning Algorithms]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/friction-feature-machine-learning-algorithms/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/friction-feature-machine-learning-algorithms/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Friction often has a negative connotation in user experience design, but it actually has many benefits. Its best-known use case is mitigating unintended consequences in high-risk scenarios, yet it has a new place in the age of artificial intelligence. Adding strategic friction to interfaces can lead to profound efficiency gains in machine learning algorithms.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Maximillian Piras)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing Accessible Text Over Images: Best Practices, Techniques, And Resources (Part 1)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/designing-accessible-text-over-images-part1/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/designing-accessible-text-over-images-part1/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this two-part series of articles, Hannah Milan covers the best practices when using various accessible text over images techniques for designing your web and mobile app content.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Hannah Milan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How We Optimized Performance To Serve A Global Audience]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/optimize-performance-serve-global-audience/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/optimize-performance-serve-global-audience/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Liran Cohen and the team at Bookaway, a travel booking service, dramatically improved their site’s performance by auditing Core Web Vitals. In this article, Liran shares his team’s process for auditing and monitoring Web Vitals and the effort it took to dramatically improve Bookaway’s performance — and the benefits that came with it.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Liran Cohen)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smashing Podcast Episode 64 With Alvin Bryan: What Is A Headless CMS?]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/smashing-podcast-episode-64/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/smashing-podcast-episode-64/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re talking about headless content management systems. What are they, and how do they differ from more traditional systems? Drew McLellan talks to Alvin Bryan to find out.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Drew McLellan)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS And Accessibility: Inclusion Through User Choice]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/css-accessibility-inclusion-user-choice/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/08/css-accessibility-inclusion-user-choice/"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Carie Fisher outlines which CSS media features are available for detecting user preferences and how they are used to design and build more inclusive user experiences.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Carie Fisher)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living In The Moment (August 2023 Wallpapers Edition)]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-august-2023/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/desktop-wallpaper-calendars-august-2023/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T09:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New month, new wallpapers! In this post, you’ll find unique and inspiring wallpapers for August 2023. Created with love by the community for the community, they come in versions with and without a calendar. Enjoy!]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Cosima Mielke)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Define An Array Of Colors With CSS]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/define-array-colors-css/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/define-array-colors-css/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join Temani Afif on experiment with modern CSS features to create an array of colors. The goal is to define a comma-separated list of colors and iterate through them using an index.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Temani Afif)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Use Artificial Intelligence And Machine Learning To Summarize Chat Conversations]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-summarize-chat-conversations/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-summarize-chat-conversations/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, we’ll explore how to build a chat summarizer using the Cohere API and deploy it as a web application using Gradio.[ Cohere](https://cohere.com/) is an AI platform that provides state-of-the-art natural language processing models for a variety of tasks, including summarization. We’ll cover the steps involved in training the summarizer using sample chat conversations, interacting with the Cohere API to generate summaries, and creating a user-friendly interface using [Gradio](https://www.gradio.app/).]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Joas Pambou)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modern Technology And The Future Of Language Translation]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/modern-technology-future-language-translation/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/modern-technology-future-language-translation/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The field of language translation has never been more exciting. Explore the evolution of language translation platforms, how we got to where we are today, and what advancements we can look forward to in the coming years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adriano Raiano)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recreating YouTube’s Ambient Mode Glow Effect]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/recreating-youtube-ambient-mode-glow-effect/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/recreating-youtube-ambient-mode-glow-effect/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, Adrian deconstructs YouTube’s “Ambient Mode” feature and how HTML `` and the `requestAnimationFrame` function are used to create the glowing effect.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Adrian Bece)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Art Of Looking Back: A Critical Reflection For Individual Contributors]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/critical-reflection-individual-contributors/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/critical-reflection-individual-contributors/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover the importance of critical reflective practice and challenge some beliefs about reflection and its role in our work and growth. Kristian Mikhel suggests a critical reflective routine for individual contributors and gives some practical recommendations that will make reflection meaningful and actionable.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Kristian Mikhel)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing Age-Inclusive Products: Guidelines And Best Practices]]></title>
        <id>https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/designing-age-inclusive-products-guidelines-best-practices/</id>
        <link href="https://smashingmagazine.com/2023/07/designing-age-inclusive-products-guidelines-best-practices/"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With an estimated one in every eight individuals worldwide surpassing the age of 60, who are actively adopting online shopping, the need for user-friendly interfaces tailored to their needs becomes apparent. Explore the guidelines to help you design inclusive products for all, particularly for an older audience and your future self.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>hello@smashingmagazine.com (Michal Halperin Ben Zvi)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>